<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tobybase: A Tech Blog on Tobybase: A Tech Blog</title>
    <link>http://tobybase.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tobybase: A Tech Blog on Tobybase: A Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Post with an image, from my phone</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2019/02/28/post-with-an-image-from-my-phone/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2019/02/28/post-with-an-image-from-my-phone/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://tobybase.com/uploads/3733E349-20DF-4B4C-BEF1-220AFF570BE1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test post with image from my phone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Update From Forestry.io Website</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2019/02/28/update-from-forestry.io-website/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2019/02/28/update-from-forestry.io-website/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Updating from the Forestry.io website&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>my title</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2019/02/28/my-title/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2019/02/28/my-title/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;hey you&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>A third post from my laptop; should not overwrite the other two from forestry.io</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2019/02/28/a-third-post-from-my-laptop-should-not-overwrite-the-other-two-from-forestry.io/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2019/02/28/a-third-post-from-my-laptop-should-not-overwrite-the-other-two-from-forestry.io/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Content of the file goes here&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Another update from my laptop</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2019/02/28/another-update-from-my-laptop/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2019/02/28/another-update-from-my-laptop/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Content of the file goes here&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Testing Update From Laptop</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2019/02/28/testing-update-from-laptop/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2019/02/28/testing-update-from-laptop/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Updating from my laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Linklog: They Don&#39;t Need ML</title>
          <link>http://tobybase.com/link/2018-05-01-sql-over-ml/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 09:05:54 -0500</pubDate>
          <author>Celestine Omin</author>
          <guid>http://tobybase.com/link/2018-05-01-sql-over-ml/</guid>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will write a query like select from order table where last shop date is 3 or greater months. When we get this information, we will send a nice &amp;ldquo;we miss you, come back and here&amp;rsquo;s X Naira voucher&amp;rdquo; email. The conversation rate for this one was always greater than 50%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So-called artificial intelligence and machine learning tools are in fashion these days, and the impetus is to apply them to all problem sets. It would be a mistake to think that they &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt;, or even &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt;, substitute for rational thought and human insight. Most problems are simple, and do not require complex systems to solve. (I&amp;rsquo;ve been surprised upon learning how commonsensical are the actual rules that inform predictive analyses, recommendation engines, and relationship graphs.) Good business analysis yields teachable results, not &amp;ldquo;magic&amp;rdquo; numbers or inscrutable algorithms. Human intelligence should not be set aside when pursuing the benefits of machine intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Linklog: Finland is killing its world-famous basic income experiment	</title>
          <link>http://tobybase.com/link/2018-04-19-finland-dumps-basic-income/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 15:18:45 -0500</pubDate>
          <author>Karin Olli-Nilsson @businessinsider.com</author>
          <guid>http://tobybase.com/link/2018-04-19-finland-dumps-basic-income/</guid>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, a growing number of tech entrepreneurs have endorsed universal basic income (UBI), a system system in which every individual receives a standard amount of money, simply for being alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tech moguls recognize that UBI, as well as combatting poverty, could also help solve the problem of increased robotization in the workforce, a problem they are very much part of creating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be interesting. Official results of the experiment are to be published in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The push for a universal basic income comes from economically skeptical left-leaning millennials, and industrialists who see in workforce automation their answer to the problems of human labor — the need to provision, maintain, scale, and accommodate large numbers of comparatively inefficient workers, with all of their troubles and demands. Widespread automation would allow for an even greater profit efficiency than &lt;em&gt;slavery&lt;/em&gt;, without any of the associated ethical considerations — provided, of course, that the masses of dispossessed workers are maintained in a kind of minimally acceptable lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Linklog: Oracle Sees Autonomous Database Changing DBA Roles for the Good</title>
          <link>http://tobybase.com/link/2018-04-10-oracle-sees-automation/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 12:47:23 -0500</pubDate>
          <author>Lindsay Moore</author>
          <guid>http://tobybase.com/link/2018-04-10-oracle-sees-automation/</guid>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the tactical tasks are reduced &amp;ndash; or even eliminated &amp;ndash; DBAs will have more time to spend on higher level tasks, like data security, data lifecycle management, data architecture and data modeling, Colgan said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t be too worried about automation replacing the need for database professionals. The first time I recall hearing such claims was in 1999 with the advent of Oracle 9i. If what Colgan says is true, and there is every reason to believe it is, then the day to day work of DBAs and consultants like myself is only bound to become more interesting and productive. All of those things she mentions — particularly security — deserve far more attention than they receive in most organizations, as underfunded and overwhelmed as they are with routine operational tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title></title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2018/04/10/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2018/04/10/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://tobybase.com/img/2018-04-10-oci-add-block-volume-on-windows/access-denied.jpg&#34; width=&#34;800px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are getting the above error when trying to add a block volume to a Windows VM in Oracle Cloud Infrastructure, the solution is quite simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran across this problem recently when configuring a Windows virtual machine on Oracle Cloud for the first time. I needed some additional storage, so I added a SCSI block volume that gave me what I required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://tobybase.com/img/2018-04-10-oci-add-block-volume-on-windows/attached-block-volumes.jpg&#34; width=&#34;800px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After attaching the block volume to the compute instance, I clicked on the elipsis to the right of the volume overview panel, and selected &lt;em&gt;iSCSI Commands &amp;amp; Information&lt;/em&gt; as shown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://tobybase.com/img/2018-04-10-oci-add-block-volume-on-windows/iscsi-commands.jpg&#34; width=&#34;586px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to make use of your attached volume, the commands shown in the &lt;em&gt;Attach Commands&lt;/em&gt; pane must be run from a Powershell or Command terminal, after which you can format and mount the volume according to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.us-phoenix-1.oraclecloud.com/Content/Block/Tasks/connectingtoavolume.htm&#34;&gt;online instructions provided by Oracle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://tobybase.com/img/2018-04-10-oci-add-block-volume-on-windows/powershell-button.jpg&#34; width=&#34;369px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when I clicked on the Powershell terminal icon in the Windows Taskbar and attempted to run the iSCSI commands, I got the following error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Set-Service: : Service &#39;Microsoft iSCSI Initiator Service (msiscsi)&#39; cannot be configured due to the following error: Access is denied
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that the iSCSI commands Oracle provides need to be run from a privileged terminal, or &amp;ldquo;elevated shell&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://tobybase.com/img/2018-04-10-oci-add-block-volume-on-windows/run-as-admin.jpg&#34; width=&#34;800px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search for Powershell. Right-click on the icon, and choose &lt;em&gt;Run as administrator&lt;/em&gt;. You will now be able to successfully run the iSCSI commands and connect to your block volume. If you don&amp;rsquo;t care for that method, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.top-password.com/blog/5-ways-to-run-powershell-as-administrator-in-windows-10/&#34;&gt;there are a number of other ways&lt;/a&gt; to launch an elevated shell in Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun experimenting with OCI. There is no better cost/performance value for cloud infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Linklog: 2107 Was Bad for Facebook. 2018 Will Be Worse.</title>
          <link>http://tobybase.com/link/2017-12-15-2018-bad-year-for-facebook/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Bloomberg</author>
          <guid>http://tobybase.com/link/2017-12-15-2018-bad-year-for-facebook/</guid>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Facebook remains the biggest platform, Google and Twitter are facing similar pressure from governments in the U.S. and in Europe. Germany enacted a law requiring the social networks to remove hate speech promptly or face fines. In the U.S., the activities of a Russian troll farm during the 2016 election campaign prompted scrutiny of Facebook&amp;rsquo;s ad selling practices and a (rather ham-handed) legislative attempt to force some transparency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has an incentive for fostering the growth and continued success of big social media platforms like Facebook and Twitter, because they operate essentially as large data warehouses on social thought, connections and behavior — supplying information that might be difficult or illegal to collect otherwise. Because of the monopoly these companies have on online self expression, and the potentially large and instantaneous impact of that form of expression, they serve as easy chokepoints for controlling the dissemination of ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Linklog: on YouTube</title>
          <link>http://tobybase.com/link/2017-12-14-infolob-youtube/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Infolob</author>
          <guid>http://tobybase.com/link/2017-12-14-infolob-youtube/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;If you find this content helpful, do the like and subscribe thing to stay informed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Move Your VM to Oracle Cloud - Part 4</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2017/03/10/move-your-vm-to-oracle-cloud-part-4/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2017/03/10/move-your-vm-to-oracle-cloud-part-4/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last of a four-part video series, our Director of Cloud Services Brian Hill creates a new compute instance in Oracle Cloud Compute Services based on his custom Windows virtual machine image.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/c1_2foZ7MQc&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Move Your VM to Oracle Cloud - Part 3</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2017/03/10/move-your-vm-to-oracle-cloud-part-3/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2017/03/10/move-your-vm-to-oracle-cloud-part-3/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;In part three of a four-part video series, our Director of Cloud Services Brian Hill creates a bootable storage volume in Oracle Cloud Compute Services with his new Windows image.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/mwsMputHP-M&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Move Your VM to Oracle Cloud - Part 2</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2017/03/10/move-your-vm-to-oracle-cloud-part-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2017/03/10/move-your-vm-to-oracle-cloud-part-2/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;In part two of a four-part video series, our Director of Cloud Services Brian Hill creates an image in Oracle Cloud Compute Services based on a Windows virtual machine.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/bA7zyOh-JiY&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
