<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>virtual machines on 👨🏻‍💻 Tobybase</title>
    <link>http://tobybase.com/tags/virtual-machines/</link>
    <description>Recent content in virtual machines on 👨🏻‍💻 Tobybase</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 13:41:02 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://tobybase.com/tags/virtual-machines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Share Files Between a Photon OS VM and the VM Host</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/share-files-between-photon-vm-and-host/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 13:41:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/share-files-between-photon-vm-and-host/</guid>
      <description>(The following is adapted from the official Photon OS FAQ.)
How do I transfer or share files between #Photon and my host machine? Use vmhgfs-fuse to transfer files between Photon and your host machine:
Enable Shared folders in the Workstation or Fusion UI (edit the VM settings and choose Options-&amp;gt;Enabled shared folders).
Make sure open-vm-tools is installed (it is installed by default in the Minimal installation and OVA import).
Run vmware-hgfsclient to list the shares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Configure Static Networking in a Linux VM</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/configure-static-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 16:36:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/configure-static-networking/</guid>
      <description>I originally had this requirement after creating a new persistent linux virtual machine in OVM that needed static addressing. This is just standard linux setup, though, and can be adapted to both virtual and physical machines.
Turn on Networking # sudo vi /etc/sysconfig/network Make sure networking is enabled and configure the hostname.
NETWORKING=yes HOSTNAME=myhost.mycompany.local Configure the Network Interface # sudo vi /etc/sysconfig/network-scripts/ifcfg-eth0 Here is a sample config for static IPs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access Denied Attaching Block Volume to Windows VM in OCI</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2018-04-10-oci-add-block-volume-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2018-04-10-oci-add-block-volume-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are getting the above error when trying to add a block volume to a Windows VM in Oracle Cloud Infrastructure, the solution is quite simple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move Your VM to Oracle Cloud - Part 4</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/infolob-lift-and-shift-howto-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/infolob-lift-and-shift-howto-4/</guid>
      <description>In the last of a four-part video series, our Director of Cloud Services Brian Hill creates a new compute instance in Oracle Cloud Compute Services based on his custom Windows virtual machine image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move Your VM to Oracle Cloud - Part 3</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/infolob-lift-and-shift-howto-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/infolob-lift-and-shift-howto-3/</guid>
      <description>In part three of a four-part video series, our Director of Cloud Services Brian Hill creates a bootable storage volume in Oracle Cloud Compute Services with his new Windows image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move Your VM to Oracle Cloud - Part 2</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/infolob-lift-and-shift-howto-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/infolob-lift-and-shift-howto-2/</guid>
      <description>In part two of a four-part video series, our Director of Cloud Services Brian Hill creates an image in Oracle Cloud Compute Services based on a Windows virtual machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move Your VM to Oracle Cloud - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/infolob-lift-and-shift-howto-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/infolob-lift-and-shift-howto-1/</guid>
      <description>In part one of a four-part video series, our Director of Cloud Services Brian Hill demonstrates how to prepare your virtual machine for upload to the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Infolob YouTube Channel</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/infolob-youtube-channel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/infolob-youtube-channel/</guid>
      <description>I am honored to work with some wonderful and truly smart folks over at Infolob in Irving, Texas. The company recently started a YouTube channel and we are looking to add lots of great videos soon for your enjoyment and education.
Check us out!
In this short Oracle Platinum Partner Spotlight video, our Chief Technologist Tim Fox explains what we do as a company and the kinds of services we provide.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
