<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on 👨🏻‍💻 Tobybase</title>
    <link>http://tobybase.com/categories/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on 👨🏻‍💻 Tobybase</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 12:01:34 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://tobybase.com/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Invalid Format&#39; Error Connecting to Server with SSH and Private Key</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/invalid-format-connecting-to-server-with-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 12:01:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/invalid-format-connecting-to-server-with-ssh/</guid>
      <description>If you get an &amp;lsquo;invalid format&amp;rsquo; error when trying to SSH in to a remote server using a private key file that you know is valid, it may be because the key was generated with PuTTY.
If the key begins with PuTTY-User-Key-File and you are using SSH/openSSH (ie. command line SSH) to connect to your server, you will need to first convert the key file using the puttygen tool that comes with PuTTY.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Share Files Between a Photon OS VM and the VM Host</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/share-files-between-photon-vm-and-host/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 13:41:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/share-files-between-photon-vm-and-host/</guid>
      <description>(The following is adapted from the official Photon OS FAQ.)
How do I transfer or share files between #Photon and my host machine? Use vmhgfs-fuse to transfer files between Photon and your host machine:
Enable Shared folders in the Workstation or Fusion UI (edit the VM settings and choose Options-&amp;gt;Enabled shared folders).
Make sure open-vm-tools is installed (it is installed by default in the Minimal installation and OVA import).
Run vmware-hgfsclient to list the shares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Configure Static Networking in a Linux VM</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/configure-static-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 16:36:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/configure-static-networking/</guid>
      <description>I originally had this requirement after creating a new persistent linux virtual machine in OVM that needed static addressing. This is just standard linux setup, though, and can be adapted to both virtual and physical machines.
Turn on Networking # sudo vi /etc/sysconfig/network Make sure networking is enabled and configure the hostname.
NETWORKING=yes HOSTNAME=myhost.mycompany.local Configure the Network Interface # sudo vi /etc/sysconfig/network-scripts/ifcfg-eth0 Here is a sample config for static IPs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
