<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Java on 👨🏻‍💻 Tobybase</title>
    <link>http://tobybase.com/tags/java/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Java on 👨🏻‍💻 Tobybase</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 16:47:39 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tobybase.com/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix High CPU Usage / Memory Leak in SQL Developer 18&#43; for Windows</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/sqldev-memory-leak/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 16:47:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/sqldev-memory-leak/</guid>
      <description>If you run SQL Developer on Windows and experience high CPU usage and/or memory leak issues that freeze your PC, then you might want to try disabling some features that are likely causing the problem.
I have personally observed this behavior on every version of SQL Developer since 18.2. Only my PC laptop is affected; my Macbook installation runs fine. I use the prepackaged Java 8 JDK. I have several colleagues who run the same configuration on Windows with no issues at all, so go figure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix SQL Developer on a Retina Display Mac(book)</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2013-07-19-fix-sql-developer-on-a-retina-display-macbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 22:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2013-07-19-fix-sql-developer-on-a-retina-display-macbook/</guid>
      <description>I just purchased a new Macbook Pro 13-inch with Retina Display and was horrified to see how fuzzy SQL Developer looked on the high-res screen. Thanks to Thunderforge on the Stack Overflow forums for this tip:
 Java 7u40 Early Access now supports HiDPI (Retina) displays, as shown by this changelog. So retina support is now available on Java 6, Java 7u40 or higher, and Java 8.
 I am currently running the Early Adopter release of SQL Developer 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Run Oracle Forms 11g Applications on OS X Lion</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-07-12-run-oracle-forms-11g-applications-on-os-x-lion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 22:28:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-07-12-run-oracle-forms-11g-applications-on-os-x-lion/</guid>
      <description>Need to run your company&amp;rsquo;s Oracle Forms application from your Mac, and can&amp;rsquo;t? Annoyed with having to crank up a virtual machine for just that one task? Even with the latest published Java version for OS X (1.6.0_33, as of today), you may find that some of the newer Forms applications just won&amp;rsquo;t run. Well, fret no longer. A solution may already be here, at least for Safari and Firefox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering Command-line Java Profiling Tools</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-05-02-discovering-command-line-java-profiling-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 21:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-05-02-discovering-command-line-java-profiling-tools/</guid>
      <description>At my current client I am responsible for administering a third-party Java appplication that unfortunately generates a lot of performance complaints. It&amp;rsquo;s a multi-tiered system with the middle-tier running on Oracle Appication Server 10.1.3. I am already familiar with GUI profiling tools like jconsole and jvisualvm, both of which are included with Oracle&amp;rsquo;s JDK, and I have played around with the profiling capabilities in NetBeans. All of these profiling tools are fairly similar to one another in look and functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invalidating Toplink Session Cache To Avoid Stale Data</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-03-09-invalidating-toplink-session-cache-to-avoid-stale-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2012 18:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-03-09-invalidating-toplink-session-cache-to-avoid-stale-data/</guid>
      <description>Toplink is a Java framework that maps objects to database tables. It is the reference implementation for the Java Persistence Architecture, or JPA. Developers use Toplink to manage data persistence (storage), queries, and transactions in an Oracle database. By default, Toplink makes use of a special cache called a Session Cache, maintained on the server, which is meant to speed up performance. Queried data is stored in the Session Cache and used in subsequent queries to reduce or eliminate calls to the database.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>