<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SQL on 👨🏻‍💻 Tobybase</title>
    <link>http://tobybase.com/categories/sql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SQL on 👨🏻‍💻 Tobybase</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 10:22:08 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://tobybase.com/categories/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Translating Teradata&#39;s MDIFF Function to Oracle SQL</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/translating-mdiff-to-oracle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 10:22:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/translating-mdiff-to-oracle/</guid>
      <description>Teradata defines its MDIFF function as follows:
MDIFF
Returns the moving difference between the specified value expression for the current row and the preceding width rows for each row in the partition.
Here &amp;ldquo;the preceding width rows&amp;rdquo; means something like the preceding n rows, where n is sometimes interpreted as the sum of all of the preceding rows, but generally as the value of the last row.
Teradata&amp;rsquo;s docs also has this to say about MDIFF:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Example of Dynamic SQL Using a CLOB</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/dynamic-sql-with-clob/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 13:28:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/dynamic-sql-with-clob/</guid>
      <description>You might not know this, but you can use the EXECUTE IMMEDIATE command with a CLOB, the same as with a VARCHAR2 variable.
declare l_sql clob; l_str1 varchar2(32767); l_str2 varchar2(32767); begin dbms_lob.createtemporary(l_sql, false); l_str1 := &amp;#39;some large SQL chunk&amp;#39;; l_str2 := &amp;#39;and the rest of large SQL chunk&amp;#39;; l_sql := l_str1; dbms_lob.writeappend(l_sql, length(l_str2), l_str2); execute immediate l_sql; dbms_lob.freetemporary(l_sql); end; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Tips for Running SAS Queries on Oracle</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/sas-exadata-performance-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 13:54:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/sas-exadata-performance-tips/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know a whole lot about SAS, but on my current gig I am frequently called upon to tune queries that run in that environment. Here are three things I have learned to keep in mind as a SAS developer when running against Oracle database.
Use PRESERVE_COMMENTS This is most critical. In Oracle, SQL hints are specified in a specially formatted inline comment. Running a query or DML statement without those hints could be detrimental to performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Use SQL to Query an XML Document Using Oracle External Tables</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-11-14-query-an-xml-file-like-an-external-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-11-14-query-an-xml-file-like-an-external-table/</guid>
      <description>Oracle&amp;rsquo;s external table feature allows you to treat structured files on the database server as tables for query and DML purposes. To use an example from the linked documentation, a tab-delimited file like this:
56 november, 15, 1980 baker mary alice 09/01/2004 87 december, 20, 1970 roper lisa marie 01/01/1999 &amp;hellip;could be queried like this:
SELECT employee_number, employee_first_name, substr(employee_middle_name, 1, 1), employee_last_name, employee_hire_date, to_date(employee_dob,&amp;#39;month, dd, yyyy&amp;#39;) FROM employees; After defining the external table like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use DML Error Logging</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-06-07-dml-error-logging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 17:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-06-07-dml-error-logging/</guid>
      <description>Introduced with Oracle 10gR2, DML Error Logging allows you to make standard SQL INSERT, UPDATE, and MERGE statements behave more like the SQL*Loader utility, logging errors to a table rather than failing and rolling back the first time an error condition is encountered.
The syntax is the same for all DML statements. Just add the following clause to the end of your DML:
LOG ERRORS The database will automatically create an error log table for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Table Functions: 9i Feature Worth Revisiting (Part 2)</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-04-27-table-functions-9i-feature-worth-revisiting-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 22:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-04-27-table-functions-9i-feature-worth-revisiting-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In part one of this series I showed a simple example of how table functions can be used to treat PL/SQL collection types as tables in a SQL query. We used a nested table collection type to which we manually added a few entries. In this example, I intend to show a more practical use of table functions using all three PL/SQL collection types: associative arrays, nested tables, and VARRAYs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Table Functions: 9i Feature Worth Revisiting (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-04-27-table-functions-9i-feature-worth-revisiting-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 22:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-04-27-table-functions-9i-feature-worth-revisiting-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Yes, they&amp;rsquo;ve been around for a while, but if you haven&amp;rsquo;t made use of table functions lately you might want to reacquaint yourself with this old gem. Table functions allow you to query the contents of PL/SQL collection types using SQL&amp;rsquo;s TABLE operator. Here is a simple example.
CREATE OR REPLACE PACKAGE example AS TYPE nested_table_typ IS TABLE OF VARCHAR2(100); FUNCTION get_nested_table_data RETURN nested_table_typ PIPELINED; END example; / CREATE OR REPLACE PACKAGE BODY example AS FUNCTION get_nested_table_data RETURN nested_table_typ PIPELINED IS BEGIN PIPE ROW (&amp;#39;one&amp;#39;); PIPE ROW (&amp;#39;two&amp;#39;); PIPE ROW (&amp;#39;three&amp;#39;); RETURN; END get_nested_table_data; END example; / The package function example.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
