<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bi on 👨🏻‍💻 Tobybase</title>
    <link>http://tobybase.com/tags/bi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bi on 👨🏻‍💻 Tobybase</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 21:47:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tobybase.com/tags/bi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Reset Page Numbering Between Document Sections in BI Publisher&#39;s Template Builder for Word</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2013-06-14-resetting-page-numbering-between-document-sections-in-bi-publishers-template-builder-for-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 21:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2013-06-14-resetting-page-numbering-between-document-sections-in-bi-publishers-template-builder-for-word/</guid>
      <description>Under normal circumstances, it is fairly easy in Microsoft Word to reset page numbering when starting a new section of your document. However, such a simple thing can be non-trivial when dealing with the BI Publisher Template Builder plugin for Microsoft Office (available from Oracle — see BI Publisher Desktop).
In short, doing this the normal way did not work for me, and in researching the issue I ran across a number of folks who were having the same problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Restrict Access to BI Publisher Reports</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-11-12-restricting-access-to-bi-publisher-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 18:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-11-12-restricting-access-to-bi-publisher-reports/</guid>
      <description>In my last post I described how to configure BI Publisher to authenticate against an LDAP server, typically a corporate Active Directory server. Aside from authentication, you can also use LDAP group membership to determine who has access to a given report. Here&amp;rsquo;s how you do it.
 Create a group in your LDAP/AD directory and assign your target users to that group. Revisit your LDAP authentication settings. These are located on the Admin Tab, on the Security Configuration page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Avoid the &#34;Job scheduling failed because the user has no permission to access this report&#34; Error in BI Publisher</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-08-27-bi-publisher-job-scheduling-failed-because-the-user-has-no-permission-to-access-this-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 20:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-08-27-bi-publisher-job-scheduling-failed-because-the-user-has-no-permission-to-access-this-report/</guid>
      <description>You can get this error if you are trying to schedule a report and your BI Publisher installation uses LDAP authentication.
To avoid it, make sure that the &amp;ldquo;Administrator&amp;rdquo; account you use to connect to your LDAP server is in the XMLP_ADMIN group. The LDAP settings are located on the Admin tab, under Security Settings / Security Configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>