<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Database on 👨🏻‍💻 Tobybase</title>
    <link>http://tobybase.com/categories/database/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Database on 👨🏻‍💻 Tobybase</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 17:08:16 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tobybase.com/categories/database/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect to Autonomous Database in the Cloud with Oracle Instant Client</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/connecting-to-autonomous-with-instant-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 17:08:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/connecting-to-autonomous-with-instant-client/</guid>
      <description>The easiest and fastest way to query and create data in your new cloud database is with SQL Developer Web, provided free with every new instance of Autonomous Database and Autonomous Data Warehouse in the Cloud. Second fastest would be with a local installation of SQL Developer or SQLcl. But if you want an authentic SQL*Plus environment, then you&amp;rsquo;ll need Oracle Instant Client.
You have two options for running SQL*Plus under Instant Client: download and install a platform-native version, or else run Instant Client in a Docker container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect to Autonomous Database in the Cloud with SQL Developer and SQLcl</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/connecting-to-autonomous-with-sql-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 16:59:40 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/connecting-to-autonomous-with-sql-dev/</guid>
      <description>Connect with SQL Developer Web If you don&amp;rsquo;t have SQL Developer installed, or you just want a quick and easy way to work with your new autonomous database, you can get started right away with SQL Developer Web, available from the Service Console. SQL Developer Web is a scaled down version of the desktop tool that allows you to query and enter data, run scripts, compile database objects, and monitor and administrate your database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Up and Running Fast On Oracle Autonomous Database in the Cloud</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/up-and-running-on-oracle-autonomous-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 16:58:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/up-and-running-on-oracle-autonomous-database/</guid>
      <description>Provision Your New Autonomous Database in Minutes With Autonomous Database and Autonomous Data Warehouse, Oracle is promising to leverage the power of AI and machine learning to automate upgrade, maintenance, and tuning operations in the database - vastly reducing the drudgery of DBA work and freeing up human minds to add more value to their companies. As a developer, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to wait to start experimenting with these exciting new features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Tips for Running SAS Queries on Oracle</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/sas-exadata-performance-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 13:54:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/sas-exadata-performance-tips/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know a whole lot about SAS, but on my current gig I am frequently called upon to tune queries that run in that environment. Here are three things I have learned to keep in mind as a SAS developer when running against Oracle database.
Use PRESERVE_COMMENTS This is most critical. In Oracle, SQL hints are specified in a specially formatted inline comment. Running a query or DML statement without those hints could be detrimental to performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix High CPU Usage / Memory Leak in SQL Developer 18&#43; for Windows</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/sqldev-memory-leak/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 16:47:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/sqldev-memory-leak/</guid>
      <description>If you run SQL Developer on Windows and experience high CPU usage and/or memory leak issues that freeze your PC, then you might want to try disabling some features that are likely causing the problem.
I have personally observed this behavior on every version of SQL Developer since 18.2. Only my PC laptop is affected; my Macbook installation runs fine. I use the prepackaged Java 8 JDK. I have several colleagues who run the same configuration on Windows with no issues at all, so go figure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle Sees Autonomous Database Changing DBA Roles for the Good</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/links/2018-04-10-oracle-sees-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 12:47:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/links/2018-04-10-oracle-sees-automation/</guid>
      <description>If the tactical tasks are reduced &amp;ndash; or even eliminated &amp;ndash; DBAs will have more time to spend on higher level tasks, like data security, data lifecycle management, data architecture and data modeling, Colgan said.
 I can&amp;rsquo;t be too worried about automation replacing the need for database professionals. The first time I recall hearing such claims was in 1999 with the advent of Oracle 9i. If what Colgan says is true, and there is every reason to believe it is, then the day to day work of DBAs and consultants like myself is only bound to become more interesting and productive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access Denied Attaching Block Volume to Windows VM in OCI</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2018-04-10-oci-add-block-volume-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2018-04-10-oci-add-block-volume-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://tobybase.com/img/2018-04-10-oci-add-block-volume-on-windows/access-denied.jpg&#34; width=&#34;800px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are getting the above error when trying to add a block volume to a Windows VM in Oracle Cloud Infrastructure, the solution is quite simple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix SQL Developer on a Retina Display Mac(book)</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2013-07-19-fix-sql-developer-on-a-retina-display-macbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 22:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2013-07-19-fix-sql-developer-on-a-retina-display-macbook/</guid>
      <description>I just purchased a new Macbook Pro 13-inch with Retina Display and was horrified to see how fuzzy SQL Developer looked on the high-res screen. Thanks to Thunderforge on the Stack Overflow forums for this tip:
 Java 7u40 Early Access now supports HiDPI (Retina) displays, as shown by this changelog. So retina support is now available on Java 6, Java 7u40 or higher, and Java 8.
 I am currently running the Early Adopter release of SQL Developer 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Reset Page Numbering Between Document Sections in BI Publisher&#39;s Template Builder for Word</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2013-06-14-resetting-page-numbering-between-document-sections-in-bi-publishers-template-builder-for-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 21:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2013-06-14-resetting-page-numbering-between-document-sections-in-bi-publishers-template-builder-for-word/</guid>
      <description>Under normal circumstances, it is fairly easy in Microsoft Word to reset page numbering when starting a new section of your document. However, such a simple thing can be non-trivial when dealing with the BI Publisher Template Builder plugin for Microsoft Office (available from Oracle — see BI Publisher Desktop).
In short, doing this the normal way did not work for me, and in researching the issue I ran across a number of folks who were having the same problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Button Hotkeys in SQL Developer on OS X</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2013-01-09-button-hotkeys-in-sql-developer-on-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 19:09:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2013-01-09-button-hotkeys-in-sql-developer-on-os-x/</guid>
      <description>In Windows, most applications provide menu and button accelerator keys that allow you to control the application without having to use a mouse. Java Swing apps like SQL Developer allow you to do the same, ostensibly in a cross-platform compatible manner.
One place I use this frequently is the Enter Binds dialog window that pops up when running a query using bind variables.
In Java 6 on OS X, the hotkey for pressing the Help and Apply buttons was OPTION-H and OPTION-A, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate PDF Reports for Free in Oracle Apex Using PL-JRXML2PDF and iReport Designer</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-12-18-video-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-12-18-video-post/</guid>
      <description>Using Jaspersoft&amp;rsquo;s free iReport Designer tool and the open source PL-JRXML2PDF project, you can generate PDF reports from Oracle Apex for free, without having to install the JasperReports and JasperReports Server components. Watch my video tutorial to find out how.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Use SQL to Query an XML Document Using Oracle External Tables</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-11-14-query-an-xml-file-like-an-external-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-11-14-query-an-xml-file-like-an-external-table/</guid>
      <description>Oracle&amp;rsquo;s external table feature allows you to treat structured files on the database server as tables for query and DML purposes. To use an example from the linked documentation, a tab-delimited file like this:
56 november, 15, 1980 baker mary alice 09/01/2004 87 december, 20, 1970 roper lisa marie 01/01/1999 &amp;hellip;could be queried like this:
SELECT employee_number, employee_first_name, substr(employee_middle_name, 1, 1), employee_last_name, employee_hire_date, to_date(employee_dob,&amp;#39;month, dd, yyyy&amp;#39;) FROM employees; After defining the external table like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Restrict Access to BI Publisher Reports</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-11-12-restricting-access-to-bi-publisher-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 18:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-11-12-restricting-access-to-bi-publisher-reports/</guid>
      <description>In my last post I described how to configure BI Publisher to authenticate against an LDAP server, typically a corporate Active Directory server. Aside from authentication, you can also use LDAP group membership to determine who has access to a given report. Here&amp;rsquo;s how you do it.
 Create a group in your LDAP/AD directory and assign your target users to that group. Revisit your LDAP authentication settings. These are located on the Admin Tab, on the Security Configuration page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Configure Oracle BI Publisher to Authenticate With Active Directory</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-11-12-configure-oracle-bi-publisher-to-authenticate-with-active-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 17:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-11-12-configure-oracle-bi-publisher-to-authenticate-with-active-directory/</guid>
      <description>Log in to BI Publisher as an administrator. Click on the Admin tab. Click on Security Configuration. For Security Model, choose LDAP and enter the following parameters:
   Setting Example Value     URL ldap://ad.mycompany.com:389 Your company&amp;rsquo;s LDAP server and port.   Administrator Username CN=ADMIN,OU=Users,OU=Shared Services,DC=mycompany,DC=com The fully qualified DN of the account you use to sign in to LDAP.   Administrator Password myxlplyx The password for the above account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Avoid the &#34;Job scheduling failed because the user has no permission to access this report&#34; Error in BI Publisher</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-08-27-bi-publisher-job-scheduling-failed-because-the-user-has-no-permission-to-access-this-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 20:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-08-27-bi-publisher-job-scheduling-failed-because-the-user-has-no-permission-to-access-this-report/</guid>
      <description>You can get this error if you are trying to schedule a report and your BI Publisher installation uses LDAP authentication.
To avoid it, make sure that the &amp;ldquo;Administrator&amp;rdquo; account you use to connect to your LDAP server is in the XMLP_ADMIN group. The LDAP settings are located on the Admin tab, under Security Settings / Security Configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Fix High CPU Usage by SQL Developer on OS X</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-07-20-easy-fix-for-high-cpu-usage-in-sql-developer-on-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 16:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-07-20-easy-fix-for-high-cpu-usage-in-sql-developer-on-os-x/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been fighting for a couple of years now with an annoying performance bug in SQL Developer for OS X. After using the application for a while CPU usage would spike to around 100%, even when idle. This is a known issue associated with the &amp;ldquo;Look and Feel&amp;rdquo; preference.
Basically, don&amp;rsquo;t use the &amp;ldquo;Mac OS X&amp;rdquo; setting. Instead, use the &amp;ldquo;Oracle&amp;rdquo; setting. The theme doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter.
That fixes the CPU issue, but somewhat annoyingly moves the menu out of the menu bar at the top of the screen and into the application window, a la Windows, making the interface inconsistent with pretty much every other app I use on my Mac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Run Oracle Forms 11g Applications on OS X Lion</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-07-12-run-oracle-forms-11g-applications-on-os-x-lion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 22:28:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-07-12-run-oracle-forms-11g-applications-on-os-x-lion/</guid>
      <description>Need to run your company&amp;rsquo;s Oracle Forms application from your Mac, and can&amp;rsquo;t? Annoyed with having to crank up a virtual machine for just that one task? Even with the latest published Java version for OS X (1.6.0_33, as of today), you may find that some of the newer Forms applications just won&amp;rsquo;t run. Well, fret no longer. A solution may already be here, at least for Safari and Firefox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OS X Software for Oracle Developers</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-06-27-os-x-software-for-oracle-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2012 21:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-06-27-os-x-software-for-oracle-developers/</guid>
      <description>One of the great things about working for Enkitec is that it&amp;rsquo;s a very Mac-friendly shop. When I arrived there in 2007 there were a handful of us running Macs and the attitude at the top seemed to be respectful, but skeptical. They allowed me to use my own laptop, which at the time was a 15-inch Intel Core2 Duo Macbook Pro, with the understanding that I could request a standard-issue Dell laptop at any time should the need arise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use DML Error Logging</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-06-07-dml-error-logging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 17:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-06-07-dml-error-logging/</guid>
      <description>Introduced with Oracle 10gR2, DML Error Logging allows you to make standard SQL INSERT, UPDATE, and MERGE statements behave more like the SQL*Loader utility, logging errors to a table rather than failing and rolling back the first time an error condition is encountered.
The syntax is the same for all DML statements. Just add the following clause to the end of your DML:
LOG ERRORS  The database will automatically create an error log table for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let the Database Do the Work</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/links/2012-06-01-oracle-row-vs-set-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/links/2012-06-01-oracle-row-vs-set-processing/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re writing database-driven reports for the web, Craig Shallahamer shows why you should let the (Oracle) database handle as much of your selection and transformation logic as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use SQLFiddle to Test New Features, Run Demos</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/links/2012-05-25-sqlfiddle-is-a-sql-sandbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/links/2012-05-25-sqlfiddle-is-a-sql-sandbox/</guid>
      <description>Build your own mini-schema and run queries against it Publish your experiments for your friends to tweak Try out examples from your favorite SQL book without having to create your a database Works for Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL, and SQL Server flavors  All in all, a pretty cool. Very useful for bloggers or teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ODBC Connection Fails for MS Access App on Citrix </title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-05-11-odbc-connection-fails-for-ms-access-app-on-citrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2012 20:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-05-11-odbc-connection-fails-for-ms-access-app-on-citrix/</guid>
      <description>I ran into an interesting problem recently when attempting to publish an MS Access application with Citrix XenApp. The application pulled data from an Oracle database, so an ODBC connection was created on the Citrix server. What we found was that when a non-privileged user tried to run the application, the connection failed. When the Citrix server admin ran it, however, it worked. Furthermore, as long as the admin was logged in, anybody else could run the application successfully; when he logged out, the users&amp;rsquo; connections broke again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Table Functions: 9i Feature Worth Revisiting (Part 2)</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-04-27-table-functions-9i-feature-worth-revisiting-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 22:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-04-27-table-functions-9i-feature-worth-revisiting-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In part one of this series I showed a simple example of how table functions can be used to treat PL/SQL collection types as tables in a SQL query. We used a nested table collection type to which we manually added a few entries. In this example, I intend to show a more practical use of table functions using all three PL/SQL collection types: associative arrays, nested tables, and VARRAYs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Table Functions: 9i Feature Worth Revisiting (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-04-27-table-functions-9i-feature-worth-revisiting-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 22:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tobybase.com/posts/2012-04-27-table-functions-9i-feature-worth-revisiting-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Yes, they&amp;rsquo;ve been around for a while, but if you haven&amp;rsquo;t made use of table functions lately you might want to reacquaint yourself with this old gem. Table functions allow you to query the contents of PL/SQL collection types using SQL&amp;rsquo;s TABLE operator. Here is a simple example.
CREATE OR REPLACE PACKAGE example AS TYPE nested_table_typ IS TABLE OF VARCHAR2(100); FUNCTION get_nested_table_data RETURN nested_table_typ PIPELINED; END example; / CREATE OR REPLACE PACKAGE BODY example AS FUNCTION get_nested_table_data RETURN nested_table_typ PIPELINED IS BEGIN PIPE ROW (&amp;#39;one&amp;#39;); PIPE ROW (&amp;#39;two&amp;#39;); PIPE ROW (&amp;#39;three&amp;#39;); RETURN; END get_nested_table_data; END example; / The package function example.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>