<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tobybase: A Tech Blog on Tobybase: A Tech Blog</title>
    <link>http://tobybase.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tobybase: A Tech Blog on Tobybase: A Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 12:47:23 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Linklog: Oracle Sees Autonomous Database Changing DBA Roles for the Good</title>
          <link>http://tobybase.com/link/2018-04-10-oracle-sees-automation/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 12:47:23 -0500</pubDate>
          <author>Lindsay Moore</author>
          <guid>http://tobybase.com/link/2018-04-10-oracle-sees-automation/</guid>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the tactical tasks are reduced &amp;ndash; or even eliminated &amp;ndash; DBAs will have more time to spend on higher level tasks, like data security, data lifecycle management, data architecture and data modeling, Colgan said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t be too worried about automation replacing the need for database professionals. The first time I recall hearing such claims was in 1999 with the advent of Oracle 9i. If what Colgan says is true, and there is every reason to believe it is, then the day to day work of DBAs and consultants like myself is only bound to become more interesting and productive. All of those things she mentions — particularly security — deserve far more attention than they receive in most organizations, as underfunded and overwhelmed as they are with routine operational tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Access Denied When Adding a Block Volume to a Windows VM on Oracle Cloud Infrastructure</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2018/04/10/access-denied-when-adding-a-block-volume-to-a-windows-vm-on-oracle-cloud-infrastructure/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2018/04/10/access-denied-when-adding-a-block-volume-to-a-windows-vm-on-oracle-cloud-infrastructure/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://tobybase.com/img/2018-04-10-oci-add-block-volume-on-windows/access-denied.jpg&#34; width=&#34;800px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are getting the above error when trying to add a block volume to a Windows VM in Oracle Cloud Infrastructure, the solution is quite simple.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran across this problem recently when configuring a Windows virtual machine on Oracle Cloud for the first time. I needed some additional storage, so I added a SCSI block volume that gave me what I required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://tobybase.com/img/2018-04-10-oci-add-block-volume-on-windows/attached-block-volumes.jpg&#34; width=&#34;800px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After attaching the block volume to the compute instance, I clicked on the elipsis to the right of the volume overview panel, and selected &lt;em&gt;iSCSI Commands &amp;amp; Information&lt;/em&gt; as shown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://tobybase.com/img/2018-04-10-oci-add-block-volume-on-windows/iscsi-commands.jpg&#34; width=&#34;586px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to make use of your attached volume, the commands shown in the &lt;em&gt;Attach Commands&lt;/em&gt; pane must be run from a Powershell or Command terminal, after which you can format and mount the volume according to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.us-phoenix-1.oraclecloud.com/Content/Block/Tasks/connectingtoavolume.htm&#34;&gt;online instructions provided by Oracle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://tobybase.com/img/2018-04-10-oci-add-block-volume-on-windows/powershell-button.jpg&#34; width=&#34;369px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when I clicked on the Powershell terminal icon in the Windows Taskbar and attempted to run the iSCSI commands, I got the following error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Set-Service: : Service &#39;Microsoft iSCSI Initiator Service (msiscsi)&#39; cannot be configured due to the following error: Access is denied
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that the iSCSI commands Oracle provides need to be run from a privileged terminal, or &amp;ldquo;elevated shell&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://tobybase.com/img/2018-04-10-oci-add-block-volume-on-windows/run-as-admin.jpg&#34; width=&#34;800px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search for Powershell. Right-click on the icon, and choose &lt;em&gt;Run as administrator&lt;/em&gt;. You will now be able to successfully run the iSCSI commands and connect to your block volume. If you don&amp;rsquo;t care for that method, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.top-password.com/blog/5-ways-to-run-powershell-as-administrator-in-windows-10/&#34;&gt;there are a number of other ways&lt;/a&gt; to launch an elevated shell in Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun experimenting with OCI. There is no better cost/performance value for cloud infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Linklog: 2107 Was Bad for Facebook. 2018 Will Be Worse.</title>
          <link>http://tobybase.com/link/2017-12-15-2018-bad-year-for-facebook/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Bloomberg</author>
          <guid>http://tobybase.com/link/2017-12-15-2018-bad-year-for-facebook/</guid>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Facebook remains the biggest platform, Google and Twitter are facing similar pressure from governments in the U.S. and in Europe. Germany enacted a law requiring the social networks to remove hate speech promptly or face fines. In the U.S., the activities of a Russian troll farm during the 2016 election campaign prompted scrutiny of Facebook&amp;rsquo;s ad selling practices and a (rather ham-handed) legislative attempt to force some transparency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government has an incentive for fostering the growth and continued success of big social media platforms like Facebook and Twitter, because they operate essentially as large data warehouses on social thought, connections and behavior — supplying information that might be difficult or illegal to collect otherwise. Because of the monopoly these companies have on online self expression, and the potentially large and instantaneous impact of that form of expression, they serve as easy chokepoints for controlling the dissemination of ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Linklog: on YouTube</title>
          <link>http://tobybase.com/link/2017-12-14-infolob-youtube/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Infolob</author>
          <guid>http://tobybase.com/link/2017-12-14-infolob-youtube/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;If you find this content helpful, do the like and subscribe thing to stay informed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Move Your VM to Oracle Cloud - Part 4</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2017/03/10/move-your-vm-to-oracle-cloud---part-4/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2017/03/10/move-your-vm-to-oracle-cloud---part-4/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last of a four-part video series, our Director of Cloud Services Brian Hill creates a new compute instance in Oracle Cloud Compute Services based on his custom Windows virtual machine image.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/c1_2foZ7MQc&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Move Your VM to Oracle Cloud - Part 3</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2017/03/10/move-your-vm-to-oracle-cloud---part-3/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2017/03/10/move-your-vm-to-oracle-cloud---part-3/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;In part three of a four-part video series, our Director of Cloud Services Brian Hill creates a bootable storage volume in Oracle Cloud Compute Services with his new Windows image.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/mwsMputHP-M&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Move Your VM to Oracle Cloud - Part 2</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2017/03/10/move-your-vm-to-oracle-cloud---part-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2017/03/10/move-your-vm-to-oracle-cloud---part-2/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;In part two of a four-part video series, our Director of Cloud Services Brian Hill creates an image in Oracle Cloud Compute Services based on a Windows virtual machine.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/bA7zyOh-JiY&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Move Your VM to Oracle Cloud - Part 1</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2017/03/10/move-your-vm-to-oracle-cloud---part-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 14:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2017/03/10/move-your-vm-to-oracle-cloud---part-1/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;In part one of a four-part video series, our Director of Cloud Services Brian Hill demonstrates how to prepare your virtual machine for upload to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/lwFCj0Z4JSU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Announcing the Infolob YouTube Channel</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2017/03/10/announcing-the-infolob-youtube-channel/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2017/03/10/announcing-the-infolob-youtube-channel/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I am honored to work with some wonderful and truly &lt;em&gt;smart&lt;/em&gt; folks over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infolob.com/&#34;&gt;Infolob&lt;/a&gt; in Irving, Texas. The company recently started a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLfDjdjW6RRvKYrz_aS0Jmw&#34;&gt;YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt; and we are looking to add lots of great videos soon for your enjoyment and education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check us out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this short Oracle Platinum Partner Spotlight video, our Chief Technologist Tim Fox explains what we do as a company and the kinds of services we provide.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/g6Zenoy8GGs&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Announcing… tobybase.com</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2017/01/17/announcing-tobybase.com/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 22:58:59 -0600</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2017/01/17/announcing-tobybase.com/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome one and all to my new professional blog, &lt;a href=&#34;http://tobybase.com/&#34; title=&#34;Redirects to the website you are now on&#34;&gt;tobybase.com&lt;/a&gt;. My name is Toby Marks and I work as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://oracle.com&#34; title=&#34;Oracle&#39;s website&#34;&gt;Oracle&lt;/a&gt; Consultant at &lt;a href=&#34;http://infolob.com/&#34; title=&#34;My company&#39;s website&#34;&gt;Infolob Solutions&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Las_Colinas&#34; title=&#34;Some info about sunny Las Colinas&#34;&gt;Irving, Texas&lt;/a&gt;. My &lt;a href=&#34;http://tjmoracle.tumblr.com/&#34; title=&#34;My old blog&#34;&gt;old blog&lt;/a&gt; is still up on &lt;a href=&#34;http://tumblr.com/&#34; title=&#34;Go to Tumblr&#34;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;, and there are a &lt;a href=&#34;https://tmblr.co/Z9fAmvZapPzC&#34; title=&#34;Create PDF Reports in Oracle Apex&#34;&gt;few&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://tmblr.co/Z9fAmvXEB6iL&#34; title=&#34;Query an XML File Like an External Table&#34;&gt;items&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://tmblr.co/Z9fAmvOFEN-N&#34; title=&#34;OS X Software for Oracle Developers&#34;&gt;there&lt;/a&gt; that folks still find useful. Most of the content is a bit dated, though, as I&amp;rsquo;ve been out of the blogging game for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my attempt to turn that around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I needed was a breath of technological fresh air. Something to excite me about blogging again. So as a personal challenge, and in the spirit of adopting the latest and greatest platforms, I have decided to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34; title=&#34;Hugo makes blogging fun again&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; for static web page generation. I wanted to provide a site with the fastest possible page load times by maintaining maximum control over coding and site customization. I also love the immediate feedback Hugo gives you while you&amp;rsquo;re coding a page. No more precious seconds lost on Wordpress or Blogger! The site will be hosted on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/toby-marks&#34; title=&#34;My Github repository&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;, which will provide me with version control and an easy method for synchronization with the web server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy the new site. I look forward to adding some interesting content over the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>What to do when the Juniper Network Connect app on OS X does not connect</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2016/02/04/what-to-do-when-the-juniper-network-connect-app-on-os-x-does-not-connect/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 22:50:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2016/02/04/what-to-do-when-the-juniper-network-connect-app-on-os-x-does-not-connect/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;If you use Juniper&amp;rsquo;s Network Connect app to connect to your office VPN over HTTPS, you might occasionally experience strange errors like &amp;ldquo;A software error caused the Network Connect tunneling service to terminate.&amp;rdquo; Shortly after that, the application may either crash or prompt you for login credentials again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution involves removing all of the Network Connect files and allowing your browser to download and install the app all over again, as it did the first time you tried to connect to your office VPN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note: as a precaution you may want to simply move the Network Connect.app file from /Applications to ~/Desktop, just in case your browser is not able to download it as needed.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remove all files associated with the Network Connect application, execute the following commands in Terminal.app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#888&#34;&gt;# sudo rm -rf /Applications/Network\ Connect.app`
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#888&#34;&gt;# sudo rm -rf /usr/local/juniper`
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#888&#34;&gt;# sudo rm -rf ~/Library/Application\ Support/Juniper\ Networks`
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#888&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;# sudo rm ~/Library/Preferences/net.juniper.NetworkConnect.plist&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d20;background-color:#fff0f0&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now try connecting to your office VPN again and the browser should prompt you to redownload the application. When I tried this I got an error the first time on Firefox saying the installation failed, but I was able to manually verify that the files were in place. My second attempt succeeded. Go figure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>How to Use ps to List Top Memory, CPU Eating Processes</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2013/07/24/how-to-use-ps-to-list-top-memory-cpu-eating-processes/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 21:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2013/07/24/how-to-use-ps-to-list-top-memory-cpu-eating-processes/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;ps&lt;/code&gt; command is a versatile and configurable way to look at the processes running on your system, though I&amp;rsquo;ve generally gotten by with a lazy &lt;code&gt;ps -ef&lt;/code&gt; to find out whatever I needed to know. Recently, though, a client&amp;rsquo;s server began running out of memory, and as a number of processes were running on the server, the culprit was not immediately clear. I wanted to provide them with a quick, simple diagnostic tool they could use the next time they received an alert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look at the man page for &lt;code&gt;ps&lt;/code&gt; you&amp;rsquo;ll find a number of options available for sorting the list of processes returned as well as for filtering the columns displayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://tobybase.com/img/2013-07-24-linux-unix-use-ps-to-list-top-memory-cpu-eating-processes/ac6287b65af17b95d247ea063f0aa1bfc6f106f3b69adf0ae73ed8258d3a6c7b.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some examples of &lt;code&gt;ps&lt;/code&gt; options, from RHEL 5.6:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-e&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
select all processes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
select all &amp;ldquo;child&amp;rdquo; processes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-U &amp;lt;user&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
select all processes for a specified user&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-p &amp;lt;pid&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
select by process id&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-f&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
full-format listing; adds columns and shows process arguments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-o&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
user-defined format&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many others are available, of course, but in order to keep it simple for the client I wanted to show the top 10 processes in terms of memory utilization, with the pid, memory usage, and process name displayed. Here is what I came up with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;$ ps -eo pid,user,pmem,args O R | tail -n &lt;span style=&#34;color:#00d;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here is an explanation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
shows running processes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;-e&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
show all processes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;-o pid,user,poem,args&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
show the pid, %mem, and process columns&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;O R&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
sort by memory usage (ascending)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tail&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
shows only the last lines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;-n 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
show the last 10 lines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked the concept so much that I decided to adapt it for OS X, where the &lt;code&gt;ps&lt;/code&gt; command takes a slightly different set of arguments. To my .bash_profile file I added the following lines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#038&#34;&gt;alias&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#369&#34;&gt;psmem&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d20;background-color:#fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;while :; do clear; ps -ecm -o %mem,rss,pid,user,state,args | head -n 10; sleep 5; done&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#038&#34;&gt;alias&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#369&#34;&gt;pscpu&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span style=&#34;color:#d20;background-color:#fff0f0&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;while :; do clear; ps -ecr -o %cpu,pid,user,state,args | head -n 10; sleep 2; done&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have one alias for retrieving my top memory-utilizing processes and one for my top CPU-utilizing processes. The &lt;code&gt;while&lt;/code&gt; loop in the alias implements a functionality similar to that of the Linux &lt;code&gt;watch&lt;/code&gt; command, clearing the screen and running the process indefinitely until it is forcibly quit. For my own purposes I wanted to display some additional columns, like username and process state. I also changed the sort ordering to display the largest processes at the top of the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://tobybase.com/img/2013-07-24-linux-unix-use-ps-to-list-top-memory-cpu-eating-processes/2bcd3b2c40d8bc37893b47399aed325508e95c655492de8866a8365eede7008f.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Linklog: Use Preview to view formatted man pages</title>
          <link>http://tobybase.com/link/2013-07-24-view-man-pages/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Anonymous</author>
          <guid>http://tobybase.com/link/2013-07-24-view-man-pages/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an elegant solution for viewing, searching, and archiving man pages that eliminates the necessity for third party apps.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Update:&lt;/em&gt; still works in macOS Sierra.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>How to Fix SQL Developer on a Retina Display Mac(book)</title>
            <link>http://tobybase.com/blog/2013/07/19/how-to-fix-sql-developer-on-a-retina-display-macbook/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 22:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>toby.marks@infolob.com (Toby Marks)</author>
            <guid>http://tobybase.com/blog/2013/07/19/how-to-fix-sql-developer-on-a-retina-display-macbook/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I just purchased a new Macbook Pro 13-inch with Retina Display and was horrified to see how fuzzy SQL Developer looked on the high-res screen. Thanks to Thunderforge on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/15181079/apple-retina-display-support-in-java-jdk-1-7-for-awt-swing&#34;&gt;Stack Overflow forums&lt;/a&gt; for this tip:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java 7u40 Early Access now supports HiDPI (Retina) displays, as
shown by this &lt;a href=&#34;http://download.java.net/jdk7u40/changes/jdk7u40-b28.html?q=download/jdk7u40/changes/jdk7u40-b28.html&#34;&gt;changelog&lt;/a&gt;. So retina support is now available on Java 6, Java 7u40 or higher, and Java 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently running the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/developer-tools/sql-developer/downloads/sqldev-download-v4-1925679.html&#34;&gt;Early Adopter release of SQL Developer 4.0&lt;/a&gt; which requires JDK 1.7. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what the state of Java 8 is on the Mac, so I opted to upgrade my JDK from 1.7.0_25 to 1.7.0_40. After that I had nice, sharp lines back in SQL Developer and all my other Java apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Oracle&amp;rsquo;s Java team for addressing this!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
